<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ross Knapman</title>
    <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ross Knapman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 10:07:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rossknapman.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>USA 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/usa2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 10:07:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/usa2022/</guid>
      <description>Between June and August 2022, I had the wonderful opportunity to visit Ran Cheng&amp;rsquo;s group at the University of California, Riverside, to work on a (still ongoing, at time of writing) project. This post, however, is about the exciting things I got up to when I was not working!
 The UCR Bell Tower.
  Rather than flying directly to Los Angeles, I decided that I would book my flight to Seattle, a city that I had been wanting to visit for a good decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a teenager, I was quite into photography, especially after my parents got me a Canon EOS 600D for Christmas when I was 15. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t really do so much of this at the moment, here is a collection of photos that I have taken in various places around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Inverse Search with Neovim, VimTeX and Zathura</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/nvimvimtexzathura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 16:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/nvimvimtexzathura/</guid>
      <description>There are many reasons to write LaTeX in Vim instead of the more &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; LaTeX editors. Maybe you want to type long equations quickly with the help of UltiSnips, or you just want to make the most of Vim&amp;rsquo;s many features. VimTeX is a plugin for Vim (and Neovim) which allows for the easy authoring of LaTeX files using Vim, with useful features such as autocompilation, and Zathura is a minimalist, highly customisable document viewer with Vim keybindings by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Cup to Doughnut Animation</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/mugdoughnut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/mugdoughnut/</guid>
      <description>I made this animation using Blender when writing my project proposal for my Studienstiftung application.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blender</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/blender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/blender/</guid>
      <description>Basics  The tilde key (at least when I was using an external keyboard) gives you a perspective menu.
 Shift+S gives you the cursor menu, allowing you to place the 3D cursor back at the origin, for example (this is where new objects spawn).
 Shift+RMB moves the 3D cursor
 You can create new panes by clicking and dragging the corners to drag out new panes, and merge them together in a similar way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>Constants and Variables  Can either define a constant like const double pi = 3.14 or as a preprocessor director #define PI 3.14, where the latter replaces all appearances of PI in the source code with 3.14
 Declaration of variables: int x = 0; and int x(0); and int x{0}; are all equivalent
 x = x + 1; and x += 1 and ++x and x++ are all equivalent, but y = ++x will first add 1 to x, then assign this to y, whilst y = x++ will first set y = x, then add 1 to x</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying iTerm2 Profile Between Computers</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/copyingiterm2profilebetweencomputers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/copyingiterm2profilebetweencomputers/</guid>
      <description>On the first computer, go to Preferences. Tick &amp;#34;Load preferences from a custom folder or URL&amp;#34;. Browse to where the folder should be saved (e.g. in Dropbox) - this should be its own folder (so create a folder called iTerm or something). On the second computer. Load this folder, then restart iTerm. Then the &amp;#34;Load preferences…&amp;#34; box can be unticked.
 For Alt+Left etc., go to Preferences, Profiles, Keys, and load the preset &amp;#34;Natural Text Editing&amp;#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/cron/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/cron/</guid>
      <description> Cron Job Not Working with Rsync  Grant cron full disk access by following the guide at https://blog.bejarano.io/fixing-cron-jobs-in-mojave/
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Recovery</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/datarecovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/datarecovery/</guid>
      <description>If partition table corrupted, can repair the partition table on macOS using https://www.macintosh-data-recovery.com/blog/repair-mac-external-hard-drive/?fbclid=IwAR3Yp4IDoitVQSEvgiuXgm9Edl-N8rnO4s2BjbK8GtzzzaIw9OrUkH_6cZk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Downloading YouTube Videos that are Private (but Accessible to You When Logged In)</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/downloadingyoutubevideosthatareprivatebutaccessibletoyouwhenloggedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/downloadingyoutubevideosthatareprivatebutaccessibletoyouwhenloggedin/</guid>
      <description>https://daveparrish.net/posts/2018-06-22-How-to-download-private-YouTube-videos-with-youtube-dl.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/emacs/</guid>
      <description> Org Mode  Plain Text  To show plain text without formatting, use font-lock-mode
  Checking for Link Rot  Use org-lint
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFmpeg</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/ffmpeg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/ffmpeg/</guid>
      <description>Joining Videos Side-By-Side with FFmpeg  This all also works for images
 Getting information about the video (resolution, fps etc.): ffprobe file.mp4
 Basic usage (more work needed for sound): ffmpeg -i left.mp4 -i right.mp4 -filter_complex hstack output.mp4
 If the files are of different heights: ffmpeg -i In.mp4 -vf scale=-1:&amp;lt;height&amp;gt; Out.mp4
 If the resulting width is not an even number: ffmpeg -i Out.mp4 -vf scale=iw-1:ih Out.mp4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU/Linux</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/gnulinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/gnulinux/</guid>
      <description>Determining IP Address on Ubuntu  ip addr show
  Finding out If a Command Is Available to Run on Ubuntu  compgen -c | grep &amp;lt;COMMAND&amp;gt;
  Disk Usage  In current directory: du -h . --max-depth=1 on Ubuntu or du -hd1. on macOS
  Installing GNU/Linux on an Apple Computer  On Mac, no screen when booting installation: highlight the boot option, press e, add radeon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUI Applications with X11 Forwarding</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/guiapplicationswithx11forwarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/guiapplicationswithx11forwarding/</guid>
      <description>If things are not opening, try running echo $DISPLAY on the server. If nothing comes up, a possible fix on macOS is to install XQuartz, run launchctl load -w /Library/LaunchAgents/org.macosforge.xquartz.startx.plist on the Mac, then restart the computer. For debugging, try using ssh -v -X &amp;lt;e.g. WS2&amp;gt;.
 To open the Seafile GUI remotely (annoyingly, the GUI allows adjusting some settings that the CLI does not have), run seafile-applet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Network</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/homenetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/homenetwork/</guid>
      <description> Running Pi-Hole and NextCloud on Same Raspberry Pi  Change Pi-Hole&amp;#39;s default port to something else by editing /etc/lighttpd/lighttpd.conf. Then you can still access the Pi-Hole admin panel at &amp;lt;IP address&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;/admin
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inkscape</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/inkscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/inkscape/</guid>
      <description>I can’t find the text align button, to align the text within the text box  It shows up when you’re typing the text itself, then goes away, contrary to with older versions.
  Extensions are not shown in the Extensions menu  First, make sure you’re looking in the right place. For example, Tex Text was hidden under the Text menu, and when I searched for it, I typed it as one word, so it didn’t show up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MuMax</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/mumax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/mumax/</guid>
      <description>Overlapping Regions  Say we have the default region 0, some region 1, and some region 2 that is within region 1. If we set Ku1 = 1e4, then do Ku1.SetRegion(1, 1e5), then region 2 will take 1e4. If, on the other hand, we do Ku1.SetRegion(0, 1e4) and `Ku1.SetRegion(1e5), then region 2 will take 0. To get region 2 to match with region 1, we have to separately call Ku1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ParaView</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/paraview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/paraview/</guid>
      <description>Converting ovf to vtk for ParaView  mumax3-convert -vtk binary m*.ovf
  Producing Animations from pvpython  If using ParaView version &amp;lt;5.8, you need to, headless rendering is not supported, so you need to use xvfb-run to create a virtual X environment,
 xvfb-run pvpython [SCRIPTNAME].py
 If several animations are being rendered at the smae time, you can use the -a option to start another dummy X server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDFs</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/pdfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/pdfs/</guid>
      <description> Join Pdfs Vertically  pdfjam Page1.pdf Page2.pdf --nup 2x1 --landscape --outfile Page1+2.pdf
 Then remove the margins (CAREFUL, MIGHT FAIL IF IMAGE HAS A LOT OF WHITE): pdf-crop-margins -v -p 0 -a -6 input.pdf
 (Having installed this tool using pip install pdfCropMargins --upgrade)
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>  R. Knapman, D. R. Rodrigues, J. Masell, and K. Everschor-Sitte, &amp;ldquo;Current-induced H-shaped-skyrmion creation and their dynamics in the helical phase&amp;rdquo;, Journal of Physics D: Applied Physics, 54(40), 404003 (2021). arXiv: 2105.06859.
  D. R. Rodrigues, J. Nothhelfer, M. Mohseni, R. Knapman, P. Pirro, and K. Everschor-Sitte, &amp;ldquo;Nonlinear Dynamics of Topological Ferromagnetic Textures for Frequency Multiplication&amp;rdquo;, Phys. Rev. Appl., 10, 14020 (2021). arXiv: 2012.11481.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/python/</guid>
      <description>NumPy Problems  Axis Size Not $2^N$  Problem: A thin film is represented by an array of vectors ‚a‘ with dimensions (2000 x 500 x 1), but it is not processed properly because it should really be (2048 x 512 x 1) (2^11 = 2048; 2^9 = 512). Solution: aNew = np.pad(a, [(24, 24), (6, 6)]) will surround the data with zeros to make it up to the correct shape</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/misc/recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/misc/recipes/</guid>
      <description>A collection of my favourite recipes, stored here so that I can access them easily from wherever, and send them to friends. All recipes are vegan, except where I have added a note on what to change to make it vegan, or where it is obvious (e.g. cheese to vegan cheese; butter to vegan butter or spread).
 Coconut Chickpea Curry Kale and Leek Bake Coconut Curry Lentil Soup Vegetarian Peanut Soup Lentil Soup Chana Masala Vegan Paella Bulgur Salad with Cucumbers, Red Peppers, Chickpeas, Lemon &amp;amp; Dill 1-Hour Vegan Shepherd’s Pie Vegan Fall Pasta Salad Spiced Lentil and Butternut Squash Soup Vegan Goulash with Smoked Tofu and Potatoes Mom’s Ultimate Vegetarian Lentil Loaf Texas Caviar Hot German Potato Salad Spiced Aubergine Bake Sweet and Sour Chickpeas Peppers Broccoli Hearty Mushroom Goulash Frankies Vegan Burrito with Spanish Rice Healthy 5-Ingredient Granola Bars Quick N’ Healthy Vegetable Pasta Salad Vegan Spinach and Artichoke Pasta Spicy Tomato Gnocchi With White Beans, Spinach and Vegan Sausage Vegan Garlic Noodles Easy Vegan Spinach and Mushroom Lasagna Curry Chickpea Salad Wraps with Toasted Coconut Honey Mustard Lentil Vegetable Salad (replace honey with agave or maple syrup) Vegan Mac and Cheese Vegan Sweet Potato and Peanut Enchiladas Greek Pasta Salad with Easy Greek Vinaigrette Vegan Caesar Pasta Salad with Chickpeas Vegan Butternut Squash Mac and Cheese Vegan Pumpkin Pasta with Spinach and Mushrooms Gnocchi With Garlic Tomato Sauce (but maybe double the ingredients, as this only makes enough for about 2 meals) Chickpea Frittata With Sage and Rosemary Vegan Tuna Slow Cooker Tofu Butter Chicken (Vegan) Vegan &amp;lsquo;Egg&amp;rsquo; Salad Sandwich Vegan Fajita Pasta with Chickpeas and Peppers Vegetable Cacciatore with Rotini Vegan Macaroni Salad Tofish and Chips  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reveal.js</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/reveal.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/reveal.js/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown  You can write presentations in R Markdown and export them to Reveal.js. Good tutorials for this are here and here, and the documentation with all options is here. To export the slides, you can run echo &amp;#34;require(rmarkdown); render(&amp;#39;FILENAME.md&amp;#39;, output_file=&amp;#39;index.html&amp;#39;)&amp;#34; | R --vanilla.
 To have a double column layout, you can use a stylesheet like
.container{  display: flex; } .col{  flex: 1; }  then, in the R Markdown file,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SageMath</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/sagemath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/sagemath/</guid>
      <description> Defining Functions of Variables  For example, we want to define some generic ɸ(t) without explicitly defining a functional form. Then, do phi = function(&amp;#39;phi&amp;#39;, latex_name=&amp;#39;\\varphi&amp;#39;, nargs=1)(t).
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/shell/</guid>
      <description>ZSH is Being Slow  Run
git config --add oh-my-zsh.hide-status 1 git config --add oh-my-zsh.hide-dirty 1    if [ ... == … ]; then Not Working with Posix Shell  Need single =, and need variables e.g. $directory in quotes
  I Only Want the Filename and Not the Entire Path  If you only want, say video.mp4 rather than e.g. /home/myname/long/complicated/path/to/video.mp4, use the basename command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SOCKS Proxy for Accessing Papers from Uni Network</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/socksproxyforaccessingpapersfromuninetwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/socksproxyforaccessingpapersfromuninetwork/</guid>
      <description>This is an alternative to using a VPN, which is nice in that it only routes your traffic from a single browser window (and works if the university VPN is down, which happens sometimes). ssh -D 8080 ws2 Then open Firefox, go to Network Settings -&amp;gt; Manual proxy configuration, enter SOCKS Host 127.0.0.1, Port 8080 ws2 is what I have called twist-ws02 in my SSH config. I find that a better solution is to define an alias in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/vim/</guid>
      <description>Find and Replace  Search and replace globally: :%s/foo/bar/g
 :s is the command to substitute, % means to apply within the current file, rather than just the current line, g means global, i.e. it replaces all instances, not just the first
 To find and replace regex whilst keeping part of a pattern, e.g. if you want to replace #1 #2 #3 by #1 \, #2 \, #3 \n, then need to run</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/visualstudiocode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/visualstudiocode/</guid>
      <description> Ctrl + W Not Working with Vim Mode  In Keyboard Shortcuts, disable the Vim shortcut that corresponds to this.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/website/</guid>
      <description>Public Repo as Submodule  For each submodule commit, the project updates its reference to the submodule to maintain its connection to the correct commit. Therefore, commit both the main project and the public repo, then run git push -u origin main --recurse-submodules=on-demand. See e.g. https://www.adamormsby.com/posts/000/how-to-set-up-a-hugo-site-on-github-pages-with-submodules/
  Jekyll  Does Not Run on Big Sur  A combination of these resources seemed to fix it:
 https://ernestojeh.com/fix-jekyll-on-macos-big-sur slycke&amp;#39;s answer at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zathura</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/zathura/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/notes/zathura/</guid>
      <description> Toggle Single/Double Page  Press D.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
