<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Ross Knapman</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Ross Knapman</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Figures From My PhD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/phdfigures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/phdfigures/</guid>
      <description>Here is a small assortment of figures that I made during my PhD with the TWIST and INSPIRE groups, mainly for my thesis. I started to learn Blender shortly after the start of my PhD, but I ended up switching to POV-Ray, which is the tool used to create most of the images on this page (the only exception being the H-shaped skyrmion render, for which I used Blender). Although POV-Ray is significantly older and has fewer features than Blender, I have found it to be much more simple to use where more complex mathematics is required to describe an object (with Blender, I always felt like I was having to &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; it in order to create what I wanted, even with the Python API).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Can Generate Pretty Good Music Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/udiophdsong/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/udiophdsong/</guid>
      <description>It seems like ChatGPT has been around forever now, and despite only having used it for a year or so, many people wonder how they ever lived without it. I recently discovered that a similar service exists for audio, where songs can be generated from a prompt. One example of such a service is Udio. At the time of writing, it is free to use, albeit with a limited (but generous) number of credits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Cup to Doughnut Animation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mugdoughnut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mugdoughnut/</guid>
      <description>I made this animation using Blender when writing my project proposal for my Studienstiftung application.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
