<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ross Knapman</title>
    <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ross Knapman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 10:07:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>USA 2022</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/usa2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 10:07:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/usa2022/</guid>
      <description>Between June and August 2022, I had the wonderful opportunity to visit Ran Cheng&amp;rsquo;s group at the University of California, Riverside, to work on a (still ongoing, at time of writing) project. This post, however, is about the exciting things I got up to when I was not working!
The UCR Bell Tower.
Rather than flying directly to Los Angeles, I decided that I would book my flight to Seattle, a city that I had been wanting to visit for a good decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a teenager, I was quite into photography, especially after my parents got me a Canon EOS 600D for Christmas when I was 15. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t really do so much of this at the moment, here is a collection of photos that I have taken in various places around the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Inverse Search with Neovim, VimTeX and Zathura</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/nvimvimtexzathura/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 16:49:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/nvimvimtexzathura/</guid>
      <description>Note 06.01.2023: With the release of VimTex 2.8, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t need to do this any more. See :help vimtex-synctex-inverse-search.
There are many reasons to write LaTeX in Vim instead of the more &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; LaTeX editors. Maybe you want to type long equations quickly with the help of UltiSnips, or you just want to make the most of Vim&amp;rsquo;s many features. VimTeX is a plugin for Vim (and Neovim) which allows for the easy authoring of LaTeX files using Vim, with useful features such as autocompilation, and Zathura is a minimalist, highly customisable document viewer with Vim keybindings by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee Cup to Doughnut Animation</title>
      <link>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/mugdoughnut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.rossknapman.com/posts/mugdoughnut/</guid>
      <description>I made this animation using Blender when writing my project proposal for my Studienstiftung application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
